Andrew Childre

720-560-9688 andrewchildre@gmail.com Erie, Colorado

> Email Linkedin github

Software Developer with a background in the transportation industry. I have chosen to develop a skill set that gives me the challenges I need to excel.

Profile

Establish positive working relationships with customers, vendors, and staff at all levels. Experienced in completing complex projects and multiple tasks with little supervision. Strong planning, project management, and organizational skills with the ability to act independently and solve problems before they arise. Created best practice to meet metrics that were missed

Technologies

HTML | CSS | Javascript | Material-UI | Bootstrap | Git | Github | React | Node | Mongo Express | SQL | PostgreSQL | Python | Django | AWS | VS Code | Material-UI | Jira | Slack | Heroku

Projects

Flash Cards | Michelin | Project Weather | Sprint Project

Education | Training

GA General Assembly: Software engineering immersive

United States Marine Corps: Aviation maintenance, Honor Graduate, NCO Leadership

Corporate Schools

Supervisor Leadership School Automotive Fleet Training School, Aircraft Ground Equipment training

Experience

Hazmat Tanker Transport

2020 - 2015

- Transport different petroleum products to and from different plants and refineries follow all DOT, Osha, and client safety requirements.
- Knowledge of identifying potential safety risks ahead of time.

Fleet Supervisor, FedEx Freight, Henderson, CO

2012 - 2015

- Managed Fleet of 500+ vehicles across several states, national trailer fleet, coordinate maintenance scheduling, and supervise 23 maintenance personnel with support staff.
- Optimize mechanic and maintenance schedules for greater productivity, meet dispatch schedules, and reduce maintenance costs.

Fleet Manager/Supervisor, Con-way Freight, Henderson, CO

2010 - 2012

- Managed multi-million dollar budget, fleet of 250 vehicles, national trailer fleet, and supervised 14 technicians with support staff.
- Including training, safety, service, and maintaining budget accountability while increasing productivity.

Fleet Manager/ Supervisor, UPS, Sparks, NV 2003 – 2010

- Oversee multi-million maintenance budget, fleet of 200 vehicles.
- Supervise 13 diesel and trailer mechanics that includes training, safety, service and facility spending accountability.
- Sustain a preventative maintenance program, including monitoring, reviewing, and analyzing existing procedures.
- Support UPS objectives to maximize fleet safety and performance.